

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT · AUTONOMOUS SYSTEM GROUP · THE UNIVERSITY OF TEXAS AT AUSTIN

▼ fdjeumou@utexas.edu | 🏕 franckdjeumou.qithub.io | 🖸 wuwushrek | 🛅 franck-djeumou-626613202 | 🔞 Franck Djeumou

## Research Interests\_

My research lies broadly at the intersection of learning with prior knowledge, control theory, formal methods, and optimization. Specifically, I investigate how prior knowledge (e.g., laws of Physics, properties empirically validated through engineering experiments) can be incorporated into learning agents to improve the data efficiency and generalization, and how such side information can be used for the formal verification of the agents, particularly in the context of safety-critical applications such as aircraft control and robotics.

## **Education**

#### The University of Texas at Austin

Austin, Texas, USA

September 2014 - June 2018

Fall 2018 - Now (Expected in Spring 2023)

Ph.D. IN ELECTRICAL AND COMPUTER ENGINEERING

• Ph.D. Advisor: Ufuk Topcu

- Member of the Autonomous Systems Group
- Cumulative GPA Over 30 Credits (Ph.D. Major Course Requirements) 3.967

### ISAE-SUPAERO (Institut Supérieur de l'Aéronautique et de l'Espace)

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE AND MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

- Advised by Prof. Jerome Hugues
- Cumulative GPA: 3.8 | Top 4% of the class
- Thesis on "Safety Guarantees for Drones through Set-Based Formal Verification Methods"

#### École Polytechnique

MASTER DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (COMASIC)

September 2016 - September 2017

- Advised by Prof. Eric Goubault and Prof. Sylvie Putot
- Cumulative GPA: 3.7 | Graduated with Honours
- Thesis on "Human-Embedded Autonomous Flight Under Formal Task Specifications"

## Lycée Fénelon

Paris 6e. Île-de-France, France

CLASS PREPARATORY (JUNIOR UNDERGRADUATE LEVEL) IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS, AND COMPUTER SCIENCE

· 6th out of 42 students

September 2011 - September 2014

# **Experience**

## Cosynus Team at Laboratory LIX of École Polytechnique

Palaiseau, France

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: ERIC GOUBAULT AND SYLVIE PUTOT

March 2018 - August 2018

- Build the quadrotor testbed for the team based on Crazyflie drones
- Develop a hardware and software in the loop, Gazebo-based swarm simulator for the Crazyflie drones
- Investigate safety of dynamical systems through Taylor-based methods and abstract interpretation
- · On-the-fly, lightweight, real-time verification (reach and safety properties) algorithms to be embedded on the Crazyflie drones

### **Autonomous System Group (UT Austin)**

Austin, USA

RESEARCH INTERN | ADVISOR: UFUK TOPCU

March 2017 - August 2017

- Design and build quadrotors based on the Snapdragon Platform with PX4 as the autopilot. Implementation of a fast trajectory generator for quadrotors based on the minimum snap approach and a new problem modeling
- Human interface with virtual reality and autonomous flight of a quadrotor via eye-tracking.
- $\bullet \ \ \text{Tracking of stochastically moving targets using POMDP (Partially Observable Markov Decision Process) and human input}$
- · Model checking and planning of UAVs autonomous missions with specifications written in linear temporal logic (LTL)

#### **Liebherr Aerospace and Transportation**

Toulouse, France

MACHINE LEARNING INTERN

June 2015 - August 2015

- Implementation in R of supervised learning algorithms to automatically classify aircraft's equipments from a reliability point of view
- Design and implement a human machine interface in Java that interacts with Liebherr's database and provide to a user the classification's result

## Skills

**Languages** French (native), English (fluent), Japanese (beginner) **Programming** Python, C++, C, JAVA, C#, R, Matlab, HTML5/CSS3

Tools & Technologies ROS, Jax, TensorFlow, Unity, Gazebo, PX4 Autopilot, MuJoCo, RTOS, Gurobi, Mosek, Arduino

**Sports** Tennis, Soccer, Running, Biking, Skiing



\* indicates equal contribution

# PEER-REVIEWED CONFERENCE ARTICLES [9]

2022
2021
2021
2021
2021
2021
2021
2021
2020
2022
2021
2021
2021
2021
2021

## **Honors & Awards**

2021	<b>Winner,</b> Best Demo/Poster Award at Proceedings of the 24th International Conference on Hybrid Systems:	Nachvilla IICA
2021	Computation and Control (HSCC 2021)	Nashville, USA
2017	Scholarship, Foundation of Ecole Polytechnique	Palaiseau, France
2017	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2016	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2015	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France
2014	Scholarship, ISAE-SUPAERO Foundation	Toulouse, France

# Professional Services

## **WORKSHOPS ORGANIZED**

### Workshop on Safe and Reliable Robot Autonomy under Uncertainty

Philadelphia, USA

May 2022

International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Co-organizer

### REVIEWER

I was a reviewer at the following journals and conferences.

- IEEE Transactions on Automatic Control (2021)
- International Conference on Robotics and Automation (2021)
- American Control Conference (2020, 2021)
- IEEE Conference on Decision and Control (2021)
- IFAC symposium system identification (2021)

## Invited Talks\_

2021	Incorporating Physics-Based Knowledge into Neural Network Dynamics Models,	Austin, USA
	Galois Inc: Final Briefing for the Assured Autonomy Project	
2021	Learning How to Reach, Swim, Walk and Fly in One Trial,	Austin IICA
2021	Professor Karen E. Willcox's Research Group	Austin, USA
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin. USA
2021	Lockheed Martin	Austill, USA
2021	How to learn to reach, walk, swim and fly in one trial? Well, first, admit that you are not dumb,	Austin. USA
2021	Texas Robotics Symposium	Austili, OSA
	Data-Driven, On-The-Fly Reachability and Control of Unknown Systems,	
2021	Mini-Symposium on "Leaning for Dynamical Systems and Control" at the SIAM Conference on Applications of	Portland, USA
	Dynamical Systems	
2020	Learning On-the-Fly with a Case Study in Hypersonic Flight,	Austin. USA
2020	Sandia National Laboratories: Autonomy for Hypersonics Virtual Field Day	AUSTIII, USA

# References\_

- Prof. Ufuk Topcu, Assistant Professor (Controls, Autonomy and Robotics), The University of Texas at Austin, USA
- Prof. Eric Goubault, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France
- Prof. Sylvie Putot, Professor (Computer Science), École Polytechnique, France